Guide to the John Gunther Papers 1935-1967
University of Chicago Library
- Series I: Inside Europe
  - Subseries 9: Memoranda
    - Brief Biographical Sketches of English Politicians - Neville Chamberlain Walter Elliot Samuel Hoare Leslie Hore-Belisha George Ambrose Lloyd James Maxton Herbert Samuel Oliver Stanley (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 10: Correspondence
    - Informational Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Post-publication correspondence (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Publicity "blurbs" written by Gunther (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 11: Research Notes-Abyssinian War
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 12: Research Notes-Armaments
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Notes on Skoda Works, Czechoslovakia (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Translations from foreign press (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 13: Research Notes-Austria
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Translations from foreign press (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 14: Research Notes-Balkans
    - Albania-Miscellaneous notes Bulgaria-Miscellaneous notes (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Jugoslavia-Miscellaneous notes (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Rumania-Miscellaneous notes, Rumania-Translation of Maniu speech (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 15: Research Notes-Czechoslovakia
    - Interview notes-Thomas Masaryk (President), Miscellaneous notes (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 16: Research Notes-France
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 17: Research Notes-Germany
    - Biographical sketches of Nazi leaders (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Notes on Hitler and Nazi leaders (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Interview notes-H. R. Knickerbocker (journalist) (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Notes on peace or war; economic affairs; Baltic Germans (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 18: Research Notes-Great Britain
    - Interview notes-Ballogh Interview notes-Butterworth Interview notes-Callendar Interview notes-Cesar Interview notes-Sir Walter Citrine Interview notes-Cloud (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Interview notes-Hugh Gaitskill Interview notes-Jordan Interview notes-Kuhn Interview notes-Harold Laski Interview notes-Earl of Oxford and Asquith Interview notes-Strauss Interview notes-Voight Interview notes-Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Notes on Baldwin, MacDonald, Eden, Lloyd George, Simon (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Notes on Labor Party, ILP, Communists (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Notes on Walter Elliot (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Notes on Oswald Mosely (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Notes on foreign policy (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Notes on the royal family (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 19: Research Notes-Hungary
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 20: Research Notes-Italy
    - Notes on Mussolini (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Notes on Pope Pius XII (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 21: Research Notes-League of Nations
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 22: Research Notes-Poland
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 23: Research Notes-Turkey
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 24: Research Notes-U.S.S.R.
    - Notes on Stalin (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Notes on Communist leaders Miscellaneous notes (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Interview notes-H. R. Knickerbocker (journalist) (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous notes for Introduction (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 25: Miscellaneous Materials by Others
    - Nogley Farson article on England and news dispatches (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - M. W. Fodor memoranda on Kemal Ataturk and George II of Greece (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Frances Gunther articles on Yugoslavia and Great Britain (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Edgar Mowrer news dispatches (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Ralph Forte, H. R. Knickerbocker, and miscellaneous news dispatches (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Memoranda on Mussolini and Italy (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Memoranda on Joseph Pilsudski and Joseph Beck Memoranda on Soviet Russia (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Memoranda on Great Britain (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Chronology of events, 1938-1939 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Series II: Inside Asia
  INSIDE ASIA, published in 1939, is the second of the "inside books." The materials for this work are contained in four boxes. The manuscripts are as follows:
  1. Original manuscript, typed and corrected by Gunther
  2. Printer's Copy, which is a typed carbon copy of the original manuscript (no. 1, above) with additional corrections, making the manuscript, therefore, the First Revision or the Second Draft.
  The galley and page proofs were not included in the original deposit.
  The original manuscript of the Second Edition, published in 1942, is a paste-up of the pages of the first edition with marginal corrections, numerous inserts, and a completely new chapter on Pearl Harbor.
  The correspondence numbers about eighty letters, with Gunther's brief answers attached. It comes from all over the world, mostly pointing out errors in fact, or the misspelling of foreign words or names. Several letters, especially those from Sir Sekunder Hyat Khan, prime minister of Punjab in India, and Hendrik Van Loon, are particularly interesting. One letter, from Prince Chula of Siam, discusses political affairs in that country at great length, obviously from personal knowledge.
  The research notes for INSIDE ASIA were not among the original deposit. Certain notes which deal with the 1942 Revision, as well as notes for an article in Fortune on the Middle East, are included in the collection.
  Among miscellaneous materials are several long research papers on Palestine, Japan and China, apparently done for Gunther by observers on the spot.
  - Subseries 1: Original Manuscript
    - Author's note, Table of Contents, Acknowledgments (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 1 The Emperor of Japan (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 2 Background to the Japanese (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 3 Japan's a Totalitarian Army (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 4 How Fascist is Japan? (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 5 Men of Yen (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 6 The Story of Two Twenty-Six (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 7 Japan Makes War (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 8 Guinea Pigs of Manchukuo (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 9 The Russian Position (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 10 Colossal China (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 11 Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek (Ch. 9 on ms.) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 12 A Song of Soongs (Ch. 10 on ms.) (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 13 The Chinese Reds, Who Wear Blue (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 14 Young Marshal at Sian (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 15 Course of the War (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 16 Chinese Generals and Politicians (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 17 War Lords and Puppets (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Chapter 18 Manuel Quezon (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 19 Singapore Base (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Chapter 20 Dutch Treat (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Chapter 21 The Incredible Kingdom of Siam (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Chapter 22 Mr. Gandhi (Ch. 21 on ms.) (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Chapter 23 Beginnings in India (Ch. 22 on ms.) (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Chapter 24 A Word About Religion (Ch. 23 on ms.) (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Chapter 25 Jawaharlal Nehru (Ch. 24 on ms.) (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Chapter 26 The Congress Structure (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 27 The World of the Great Princes (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 28 Aga Khan and Others (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 29 British Rule in India (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 30 The Far Frontiers (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 31 King of Kings, The Shah of Iran (Ch. 30 on ms.) (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 32 The Arab World (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 33 Kings of the Middle East (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 34 Tragedy in Palestine (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 35 Dr. Chaim Weizmann (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 36 Circumnavigation Complete (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Suggestions to Cartographer (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Text of map (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Publishers' Note (to accompany chapters submitted to Book-of-the-Month Club) (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 2: Printer's Copy
    - Chapter 1 The Emperor of Japan Chapter 2 First Course in Japanese Chapter 3 Army Bearing Pamphlets (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 4 How Fascist is Japan? Chapter 5 Men of Yen Chapter 6 The Story of Two Twenty-Six Chapter 7 Japan Makes War (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 8 Guinea Pigs of Manchukuo Chapter 9 The Russian Position Chapter 10 Colossal China (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 11 Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek Chapter 12 A Song of Soongs Chapter 13 The Chinese Reds, Who Wear Blue Chapter 14 Young Marshal at Sian Chapter 15 Course of the War (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Chapter 16 Chinese Generals and Politicians Chapter 17 War Lords and Puppets Chapter 18 Manuel Quezon (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 19 Singapore Base Chapter 20 Dutch Treat Chapter 21 The Incredible Kingdom of Siam (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Chapter 22 Mr. Gandhi Chapter 23 Beginnings in India Chapter 24 A Word About Religion Chapter 25 Jawaharlal Nehru Chapter 26 The Congress Structure (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Chapter 27 The World of the Great Princes Chapter 28 Aga Khan and Others Chapter 29 British Rule in India Chapter 30 The Far Frontiers (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Chapter 31 King of Kings, The Shah of Iran Chapter 32 Arab World Chapter 33 Kings of the Middle East (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Chapter 34 Tragedy in Palestine Chapter 35 Dr. Chaim Weizmann Chapter 36 Circumnavigation Complete Acknowledgments Bibliography (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Galley Proof Inserts (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Subseries 3: 1942 War Edition
    - Table of Contents, Preface (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 1 The Emperor of Japan Chapter 2 First Course in Japanese (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 3 Army Bearing Pamphlets Chapter 4 Japan's Totalitarian Leaders (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 5 Men of Yen Chapter 6 The Story of Two Twenty-Six Chapter 7 Japan Makes War (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 8 Pearl Harbor and the Pacific Chapter 9 Guinea Pigs of Manchukuo (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 10 The Russian Position Chapter 11 Colossal China (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 12 Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek Chapter 13 A Song of Soongs Chapter 14 The Chinese Reds, Who Wear Blue (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 15 Young Marshal at Sian Chapter 16 The War in China Chapter 17 Chinese Generals and Politicians (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 18 Puppets Look Up Chapter 19 Philippines After Quezon (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 20 Catastrophe at Singapore Chapter 21 The Dutch East Indies Under Fire (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 22 Thailand, Once Called Siam Chapter 23 Mr. Gandhi (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 24 Beginnings in India Chapter 25 A Word About Religion (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 26 Jawaharlal Nehru (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 28 The World of the Great Princes Chapter 29 Aga Khan, Moslems, and Others (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 30 British Rule in India Chapter 31 The Far Frontiers (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 32 People, Pressures, Problems in Iran Chapter 33 Arab World (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 34 Kings of the Middle East Chapter 35 Land of Israel (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 36 Dr. Chaim Weizmann Chapter 37 Circumnavigation Complete Acknowledgments Bibliography (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 4: Printer's Copy of 1942 War Edition
    - Inserts 1-35 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Inserts 36-72 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 5: Material by Others
    - Research materials on Palestine by Harry Zinder (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Biographical memoranda on Chinese personalities (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Research materials on Japan by [?] Lillico (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 6: Miscellaneous Materials
    - Miscellaneous notes on the Middle East (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Article by Gunther-"Mussolini, Moslems, and Middle East" (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous chronological notes-1939-41 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous chronological notes-1939-41 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Published pictures of Asian leaders (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 7: Correspondence
    - A-C (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - D-J (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - K-N (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - O-S (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - T-Z (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Series III: Inside Latin America
  The papers for INSIDE LATIN AMERICA, published in 1941, are contained in seven boxes. As with Gunther's first two "inside" books, there is only one complete revision of the manuscript. The manuscript material is as follows:
  2. Printer's Copy, which is a typed copy of the original manuscript (no. 1, above) with corrections-thus, the First Revision or Second Draft; and
  3. Galley proofs, corrected, but incomplete.
  During Gunther's fact-finding trip, he wrote several articles for the North American Newspaper Alliance, and made several radio broadcasts. The manuscripts of this material, some of it used, but only after complete revision, is included among the papers.
  The correspondence concerning this book is not extensive. The Informational correspondence is, however, of some interest. Gunther corresponded with U. S. State Department officials and embassy officials in the various countries he visited. There are confidential letters about the internal political scene from, among others, Claude Bowers, Ambassador to Chile; Spruille Braden, Ambassador to Colombia; Vernon Fluharty, an embassy official; Laurence Duggan of the State Department; and Overton Ellis, a legation official in El Salvador. There is also correspondence with several American journalists stationed in Latin America. The material is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. The Post-publication correspondence, for the most part, deals with minor corrections of the text.
  As in most of Gunther's other books, his major sources of information were his interview notes. Because Gunther did not list in his book, nor completely in his notes, the names of most of the persons whom he interviewed, it has been impossible to identify many of them. However, where possible, the interviewees have been at least tentatively identified. Gunther interviewed most of the Latin American presidents, numerous cabinet officials, politicians, journalists, American officials, and others. Among those interviewed were Getulio Vargas, president of Brazil; Pedro Aguirre Cerda, president of Chile; Eduardo Santos, president of Colombia; Fulgencio Batista, president of Cuba; Lazero Cárdenas, former president of Mexico; Victor Haya de la Torre, APRA leader in Peru; and Luis Munoz Karín, governor of Puerto Rico.
  Among miscellaneous materials are memoranda on individual politicians and political events prepared by newspaper correspondents for Gunther's information. These notes have been included with the material on each country and, where possible, the author has been identified.
  - Subseries 1: Original Manuscript
    - Table of Contents, Note (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 1, Inside Latin America (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 2 Fifth Column and Hemisphere Defense (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 3 Avila Camacho Succeeds Cardenas (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 4 Mexico, Land, Revolution, People (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 5 General Lazaro Cardenas (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 6 Mexicans Left and Right (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 7 Foreign Policy and Axis Influence in Mexico (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 8 Two Dictators on Top (only section on General Martinez of El Salvador) (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 9 The Banana Republics (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 10 Panama, Zone, Country, and Defense (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 11 Hail Colombia (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 12 The High Cost of Venezuela (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 13 Ecuador on Edge (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 14 What Peru Is and Isn't (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 15 Tin and Tintypes in Bolivia (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 16 Popular Front in Chile (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 17 Chile Getting Hot (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Chapter 18 Paraguay is Ruritania (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 19 The Argentine Complex (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Chapter 20 Beef, Fifth Column, and Bases (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Chapter 21 These are Argentinians (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Chapter 22 Uruguay, the Denmark of Latin America (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Chapter 23 This Is Vargas (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Chapter 24 Behold Brazil (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Chapter 25 A Word About Commodities (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Chapter 26 Brazilian Roll Call (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 27 The Coming American Imperialism (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 28 Our Orphan Island (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 29 Columbus Called it Hispaniola (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 30 Cuba's Batista (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 31 What We Should Do About It (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Acknowledgments and Bibliography (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2: Printer's Copy
    - Note, Chapters 1-2 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Chapters 3-4 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Chapters 5-7 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Chapters 8-10 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Chapters 11-12 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Chapters 13-14 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Chapters 15-18 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Chapters 19-22 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Chapters 23-26 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Chapters 27-28 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Chapters 29-31, Acknowledgments and Bibliography (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 3: Magazine Article Manuscripts
    - "Inside Latin America" (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Dispatches for North American Newspaper Alliance on Paraguay, Nicaragua, and Brazil (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Carbon copies of articles on hemispheric defense, Haya de la Torre, Gen. Camacho of Mexico, Costa Rica, and General Cardenas. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 4: Galley Proofs
    - Chapters 1-2 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Chapters 3-4 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 5-6 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 7 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 18 (28 in published edition) (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Chapters 20-22 (19, 20, 21 in published edition) (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 24 (23 in published edition) (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Chapters 27, 29 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Chapters 30-31 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Chapters 3-4 (with questions by Gunther in margin and (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Chapters 5-7 answers by "Specialists") (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Printer's copy for dummy of book (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Gunther directions for map with text (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Original manuscripts of galley inserts (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 5: Correspondence
    - Informational correspondence-A-E (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Informational correspondence-F-Q (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Informational correspondence-R-Z, and unidentified (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Post-publication correspondence-A-C (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Post-publication correspondence-D-M (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Post-publication correspondence-N-Z, and unidentified (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, memoranda in Spanish (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Review of Inside Latin America by Raymond G. Swing (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Subseries 6: Research Notes-Argentina
    - Interview notes, Norman Armour (Embassy official) Mario Bravo (Socialist leader) Spruille Braden (U.S. Ambassador to Colombia) Diaz Herrara ("Diaz H.") Col. Divine Lawrence Duggan (State Department) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Interview notes, Notes taken at "Embassy" Mason Ford Dr. Enrique Gil Horan Horsey? (U.P. Reporter) Alonso Irogoyen (Economic expert) ("I") (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Interview notes, Matson National City Bank Official Mme. Rosa Oliver Pinedo Honorio Pueyrredon (former ambassador to U.S.) Randall (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Interview notes, Julio Roca (Foreign Affairs Minister) Salazar Shaw Solandro Soronda (Fascist leader) "W___" Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Notes on Estancia Huetel; La Prensa; hoof and mouth disease (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Notes on Germans (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Biographical notes (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Biographical notes (prepared by Norman Carignan) (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Names, questions, agenda, outlines (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 7: Research Notes-Bolivia
    - Interview notes, Spruille Braden (U.S. Ambassador to Colombia) Benjamin Cohen (Chilean journalist, diplomat) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Interview notes, Dawson (Embassy official) Jenkins Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous notes; questions (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 8: Research Notes-Brazil
    - Interview notes, Adams Joao Alberto (Rio chief of police) Oswaldo Aranha (Foreign Minister) Paolo de Bettencourt (Editor, Correio da Manha) Francisco Campos (Justice and Interior Minister) (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Interview notes, Assis Chateaubriand (Newspaper publisher) Arthur de Souza Costa (Finance Minister) Crogan Paul Einhorn (Press agent, Pan American Airways) Lourival Fontes (Director of Propaganda) (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Interview notes, Hanke Walter Kerr (journalist) Knox Col. Miller Moses Naval Attache Neele Herbert S. Polin (chemist) (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Interview notes, Hart Preston (Life photographer) "Tassie" "Ted" (Embassy official) Getulio Vargas (President) (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Interview notes-Theo. A. Xanthaky (Embassy official; "Z") (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Interview notes-Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Notes on defense, bases, relations with U.S.; economy, steel; Vargas (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Biographical notes (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Biographical notes (typewritten) (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 9: Research Notes-Chile
    - Interview notes, Pedro Aguirre Cerda (President) Mervin Bohan Claude Bowers (U.S. Ambassador) (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Interview notes, Benjamin Cohen (journalist) Carlos Contreras Labarca (Communist leader) Faust Horace Graham (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Interview notes, Charles Griffin (journalist) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Interview notes, Horsey (U.P. reporter) Bernardo Leighton (Falange leader) Oscar Schnake Vergara (Socialist leader) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Interview notes, Jorge Gonzaléz Von Marées (Nazi leader) Webb (Embassy official?) Miscellaneous (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Notes on economy (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Notes on politics, political leaders (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Biographical notes (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Political and biographical notes (Prepared by Harry Tomlinson, U.P.) (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Names, questions, agenda, outlines (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 10: Research Notes-Colombia
    - Interview notes, Paul von Bauer (Head, Scadta, German airlines) Mervin Bohan Spruille Braden (U.S. Ambassador) Vernon Fluharty (Vice consul) (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Interview notes, Laureano Gomez (Conservative leader) Alfonso Lopez (Former president) Luis Lopez de Mesa (Foreign Minister) Eduardo Santos (President) Wise Wright Miscellaneous (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Notes on Fifth Column, relations with U.S.; Falange; Communists (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Biographical notes (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Typewritten political memoranda (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Names; questions (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 11: Research Notes-Costa Rica
    - Interview notes, George Chittenden Lawrence Duggan (State Department official) Overton Ellis (U.S. Legation, El Salvador) William Hornibrook (U.S. Minister) Tyler Miscellaneous (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Biographical notes; miscellaneous notes; outlines (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 12: Research Notes-Cuba